Well, hello everybody.
It's good to see I was good to see
actually a lot of you coming I wasn't
sure how many people would show up.
Usually whenever I do zoom reviews,
it's like four people So this is nice to
see that it's like a lot more than that
um If you guys see me like mute you or
anything like that, it's nothing against
you It's just you know, if I hear you,
I just end up muting you so probably had
immune melanie for a second It's just
because I see your background noise.
Um And
and so just to kind of get into this
to really talk about What I was kind
of thinking and obviously when anybody
wants to interject and say anything
you're welcome to input You know because
it's much I have a sort of a plan But
I absolutely can change depending on
what the needs of all of you is being
a this is an exam review for you guys
It's not I don't need the exam review.
It's always for you guys So let me start
with like just going through like which I
probably showed everybody in lab or showed
everybody in some form or another But
it's never a bad thing to kind of just go
through what I have on canvas just so that
like that way everybody Is aware of what
is available at the moment for studying,
so just kind of going from the basics.
So let me just share canvas real quick.
And so the 1st thing is, is looking
at, um, what I have on canvas.
So I always put a study module for you
guys together on every single test.
So for this 1 right with
exam number 1, I have.
A study guide that is kind
of below all the chapters.
So this might look different between
Monday, Wednesday, and between
Saturday, just so people know if
there's any Saturday people here,
it will still say example and study
module might be a different spot.
Um, so the first thing is.
Uh, when you're kind of going
through this, what it is to, what
to do, how to prepare for this.
Usually, what I always recommend
for everybody is, you know,
obviously go through the study
guide, which is never a bad plan.
Go through your notes, just kind of
read through everything that you've
been writing, like go through the
topics, just to really refresh your
brain as much as possible, especially
probably for those first two or
three weeks of the semester, right?
We're already on week five,
so it's a lot of work.
Let's see, kind of realize how much
you probably might have been like,
oh crap, yeah, we did cover that.
And you're going to hopefully
realize that, oh, that's actually
a lot easier than I thought it
was, uh, back then, because now
you've been using it a lot more.
Like, sig figs, for example, or
unit conversions, hopefully they're
getting a little bit easier.
You know, they're probably still hard,
but hopefully they're getting easier.
So when you're so with this test,
it's chapter one through four.
So, which is everything from the
first four weeks of the semester
for the most part, um, it's
going to be multiple choice.
So it's going to be 30
multiple choice questions.
You get about the lecture period,
length of time to complete it.
So usually I say the
time's about 75 minutes.
So, so it represents whatever
length of normal lecture time is.
Um, so.
And obviously if people get done
earlier, we'll end earlier, but usually,
usually there's always people taking
up the whole time and there's no rush
if you are like going up to that time.
No one's kind of thinking none the wiser.
And while I'm doing this, I'm
just trying to figure out where
the heck did my chat window go?
Oh, here it is.
Sorry.
I just want to make sure I had it up.
Um, So you're allowed to have, obviously,
calculator, pencils, all that stuff.
If you need scratch paper, you usually
always have a bunch with me, but
you're able to write all over the test.
You can, there's at least one blank
page in it that you can write on.
So usually people are fine, um,
when they're going through it.
The reference stuff that I'll give
you is pretty much the yellow sheet.
The only thing, I just took out a
couple things that you don't need.
Just so it's not like, you know,
Distracting you guys while you guys are
doing it, like all those, um, there's
constants that are on like the top right
hand side of the back page where all
the conversions are like, you don't,
you're not going to use any of them.
So I took it out.
Um, what else?
Uh, let's see.
So there's a study guide here.
So I would recommend like, just
skimming through it, you know, going
through all the topics, making sure
you're kind of recognizing everything.
And there's something you don't.
Whether you print it out
yourself, or if you, um, want to.
You know, even just make notes in your
notebook, I would go through all the
little things I kind of try to boil
every week Chapter down into I try to
make it less than 10 bullet points was
really the goal So which for the most
part sort of succeeded which it's nice.
It's only two pages Probably when
I first started chem 3a this thing
was like six or seven pages long.
So I'll take it.
It's a win It's a lot shorter Um, and the
way I made this thing too, it's based off
all my old exams, so essentially I took
all the major topics that I've ever tested
on, and I put it in here, and then I just
included like anything else, so I'm like,
well this is important, but I never tested
on it, but I still think it's important.
So I put all those key things
here, so that way it's not
anything that's, I don't know.
I'm, I never try to trick my students.
It's not something outta left
field or out out of nowhere where
it's like, oh, he like, he didn't,
he never showed us this thing.
Like, and there's no questions like that.
I don't see a point in doing that.
It doesn't make sense to do it.
Maybe if this was like
a higher level course.
Sure.
I want you guys to think about things, but
it's introductory chemistry for a reason.
It's meant to be introductory.
It's not supposed to be
this terrifying event.
Um.
You know, that that can happen, right?
A lot of there's a lot of teachers
that will make it into that.
That's not my goal to
make you just know enough.
So that way, when you get to physiology
or microbiology for all of us,
taking it that, you know, enough.
So you're not struggling
in that class, right?
Or if you have to go into chem 1,
a, if you're a biology major, um.
So, the other thing, too, that I
have here as well to point out, which
some people might not realize is if
you're like, hungering for practice
problems, or some of you keep like,
asking me for more and more and more.
I'm like, oh, my God, I've
given you so many things to do.
How do you need more?
So if you need more, I included
problems I recommended out of
our online textbook, right?
That's linked onto canvas.
So it goes to each chapter, and I tried
to pick the ones that do have the answers
in the, um, At the bottom of the page
for those online questions, and if anyone
needs me to show you where they're at
where the online book is, or any of that,
I can do that to here in a 2nd as well.
Um, but I did it for, like, each chapter.
So 1 thing I always kind of recommend
doing is, like, practice, whatever
you're struggling with the most, probably
for a lot of you that might be unit
conversions and dimensional analysis.
We'll talk 2nd.
Um, really?
How.
crazy will I get with these problems,
not as crazy as the homework,
just to kind of make you guys
hopefully feel a little bit better.
It's never going to be as hard as
the homework, just so you know,
it's always going to be easier, uh,
being that you did the hard part.
Now just show me that, you
know, the basics afterwards.
That's usually what I would say.
So I would recommend trying this
problems if you need extra help.
Um, other than that, though, uh, so
going back to the study module, there's
a couple things you can do to prepare.
The first thing is I have
to practice exams here.
So, um, Disclaimer, one of them
is harder than the other one.
Um, are we able to use your notes?
Not on the first test.
On some exams, I might let you use
like a note card, um, or maybe, maybe
your notes, but not on any of the,
not the individual tests usually.
Um, not for this one.
And usually the reason I always say
why, you know, because it's like,
oh man, notes would be so helpful.
Why not?
Well.
The thing I learned, you know,
through my short time teaching, is
whenever I let people use notes on
the first test, it ends up being a
nuclear explosion of failure on the
second exam or maybe the third one.
And the reason for that is because
you need to know the fundamental
skills from weeks one through
four in order to do really well
throughout the rest of the semester.
So one of the things I kind of, I always
kind of explain to all my classes is
chemistry especially, is very much
it's like a tower that you're building
up throughout the whole semester.
And if you have a really
crappy foundation, that tower
is going to fall right over.
And this is definitely one
of those classes, right?
And I kind of, and it's not going to
be this impossible test or anything.
You don't have to memorize like
a whole textbook or anything,
but it's just like, can you apply
those basic unit conversions?
Can you read the periodic table?
If you can do those
things, you'll be fine.
You don't need any, if I, if you, if
you need a formula, I'll give it to you.
If you need something that's like out
of the ordinary, I'll give it to you.
It's, you know, it's nothing that
the resource you have available,
you should be able to solve it.
Um, so for the person that
sent me that question.
Um, but going back to this
though, I would recommend doing
one of the practicums soon.
So depending on if you're
taking it Monday, you know, or
for the Monday people, I would
take it the next day or two.
Try it and see how you do.
If you're Saturday, you definitely
should be taking these like tonight.
And the reason I tell you guys to
take them sooner, you know, rather
than waiting until you study.
is as I tell everybody, I want you to
take a practice test, and I want you
to essentially fail your practice test.
I want you to take it
like it's a real test.
And you know, maybe when
you take it, you get 100%.
Amazing, your job is done, probably,
you already know probably the basics.
But the reason I say I want you to
not do as well on a practice exam is
because it shines a light on anything you
really don't understand, which is great.
It's good.
That's good to know, see what you don't
know, because it gives you that chance.
Those are question there.
I heard a voice for a second.
But it helps you kind of see, you
know, is there, what can you study?
So when you're going through it,
just write down anything that
you're like guessing on, anything
that you're not entirely sure for.
So that way you can go back
to that thing and review it.
Um, the practice tests, keep in mind,
they're not this rotating question bank.
So it's, it's literally my old exam from,
uh, practice exam ones from fall of 22
and exam number ones from fall of 23.
So they're Two old attests that I've
given to students who were in the in
your position before um exam one is a
little bit harder than exam two just
as a warning because when I first got
here I was like let's push everybody
to the level of uh like my grad
school education which is a top 10 25
university, everybody's gonna be fine.
And that was a little tougher, , a
little, little tougher.
Um, and so I kind of, you know, brought
it down more to where this level is.
I was thinking more majors level
is where I put it, and that
was a little, a little harder.
Um, so I would recommend dry trying it.
See how you do on it.
And, um, you know, once you, you map out
all those things you don't understand,
well, that's when you go study, review
your notes, go through it, and find,
seek out practice problems to help you.
Whether it's going through the study
guides, or you also have the option of,
um, in some of the different modules, so
for like different weeks, There's practice
quizzes at the bottom of multiple of them.
So like, for example, after week
one at the very bottom, there's
practice quiz number one, right?
So that's something like, it's pulling
from like a bank of like hundreds
of questions for you to do your
conversions and go through all your,
all your units and all that stuff.
And I was asked, can we
use a conversion sheet?
Yes, so you'll be
getting the yellow sheet.
It has all your conversions on it.
So you will be able to use the
yellow sheet, but it's going to be
like, it's not going to be yellow.
It's going to be white because
or whatever color exam you have.
So it's gonna be the color of your test.
Um, so for the different versions of
tests, there's like, I don't know,
I've made way too many versions.
There's like, there's what, six or
how many sections have come through.
So this, yeah.
four sections and there's
like eight versions.
I don't know.
There's a lot of them, so whatever color
you have, that's going to be the color
of your PRAC table, but you will get it.
So you'll have the practice quizzes.
So I'd recommend trying them.
Like, I think I put, I think there's.
Three of them, I want to say, that exist.
So there's one at the bottom
of dimensional analysis.
Uh, there's one at unit
conversions, and then there's one,
I think, for atoms, I believe.
Maybe it's at the end of chapter
three and four, week four, probably.
Yeah, there it is.
So there's three of them, and I
believe I put a nomenclature one in
there, too, if I remember correctly.
I did.
Okay, so there's four of them.
You have actually four different
ones they could be playing with.
Um, just keep in mind that practice
quiz number four talks about covalent
naming and there's going to be
no covalent naming on this exam.
Um, just so you know, will
we need to bring our yellow
sheet or will you provide it?
Sorry, if you already mentioned
it, I will give you one.
So just to reiterate that, um,
I will give you a brand new one.
So for any tests, if there's a reference
sheet that like, if there's not a
note card, that Type of stipulation.
I'll give you, I'll give you a blank one.
So keep that in mind.
You know, if, um, If you've been using
yours and it has 300, 000 notes on it,
you got to make sure you remember all
the things that you usually use, right?
So keep that in mind.
So like pure, uh, predictable
charges, the big one, right?
A lot of you have them written down
on there, or maybe you're using
the white, uh, periodic table.
Make sure you know those ones.
They go by the columns.
So it's usually pretty
easy to remember that.
Will we need our green sheet?
Really good question.
Um, there is one.
I think it's just one polyatomic question.
So, and I'm not giving the green sheet,
but just to let everybody know, it's
one of the, one of the, the eight ions,
and it's from the top row of the sheet.
So if that eliminate eliminates
it, limits it down to five of them.
So remember those five, you'll be fine.
That takes out 99 percent of that sheet.
So if you know that top row, um, of the
oxy anions, polyatomics, you'll be fine.
Or remember the T4 3 method.
You should be mem starting to memorize
them anyway, just so everybody knows.
I would recommend you memorize
the polyatomics for exam 2, 3,
and beyond, because you will need
them when you go to physiology.
I'm shocked at how much
they're used in physiology.
I did, I thought I figured I was
like overselling it before and now
I'm really selling it because I'm
like, Oh my God, I'm hearing from my
old students how much they're like,
Oh my God, they're in everything.
Um, make sure you start, start
memorizing, put them on flashcards.
But for this exam, only the
top row Of the top chart.
So like where nitrate is
carbonate that row I believe is
what's on that one like borate.
It's like whatever else is there.
Um, what else else can we
do in terms of studying?
Um, you're always welcome
to rewatch videos, right?
That's always the option for you.
If any of them are scored and
you want to improve, like, let's
say you didn't get a score.
Get the high enough score or weren't
getting enough things correctly.
You can always go back to them.
The ones that are scored, they
never close at any point in time.
Really.
The only time I start closing those
things is like finals week, right?
When it's, you know, all the
assignments are due and the final
happened and then they close, um,
until then you guys can open them
up at any time to review anything.
So there's always an option if you're
like, Oh, I don't really feel like.
Going through all the questions,
that's the same title on YouTube.
So on my channel, you're welcome
to go through there as well.
Um, so you have that option too.
Uh, so I always recommend that.
Uh, the other thing as well, a lot
of people don't know is that you,
once you're finished a homework,
you can always convert it into what
we, a practice homework as well.
So once the due date passes and you
don't have a late pass out, just
so you know, you can tell it to
turn it into a practice version.
Just keep in mind, once you do that,
it locks the homework grade in.
So if you're not done, don't do that.
Okay.
It's only if you're finished.
So if you see like, Oh, you got here.
you know, you're 90 percent and above when
you're homework, you're like, I'm done.
Then you can do it as a practice.
Okay, I got another question.
Um, Juan asks, when you have a
chance, can we go over homework?
I specifically need help on question
five on our current homework.
Sure, we can talk about homework.
We can go over wherever you want.
Um, like I said, this exam, if it helps
you review for the exam, I'm okay with it.
Um, sure we can do that in a little bit.
So those are kind of some of the things
that you have available to you to study.
So that alone is probably the
equivalent of 500 practice problems.
easily, if not more.
So there's a lot that
you could use to study.
So practice problems
is really Oh, did that?
Oh, it's not shared.
I moved.
So practicing problems is really the
thing that I would recommend kind of the
most for you to do, because that will
probably help more than anything else.
Will we have test questions with multiple
unit conversions and one word problem?
That's a really good question.
Um, so going off that, so one of the
things that the chemistry department
decided about I want to say a year
or two ago, and more and more of the
faculty are starting to finally do it.
I was kind of one of the first ones to
jump on board with this because I was
the one pushing it more than anything.
When it comes to unit conversions,
we really try to make it so that
they don't go over two steps in
terms of two conversions on exams.
So you can think back to all the
homework problems that you've had
that have like, Five conversions,
six conversions in a row.
The goal is to break them
down so it's only one or two
steps in terms of conversions.
So meaning, for example, what do
I consider a one step conversion?
Grams to kilograms is
a one step conversion.
Um, milliliters to liters, using density
maybe to go from grams to volume, right?
Using density, that's a one step.
Um, two or more steps is
typically dimensional analysis.
So if you had to
Well, I guess, kind of, well, not
all of you have done this lab.
I'm trying to think of lab examples,
but Maybe a two step would probably
be like, if you go to think of the
density lab, you had to, you did
the displacement method, right?
You took that little metal
object, you threw it in water,
that changed the volume.
So when you did that, you had to
take the difference of the volume, so
you had to do one step there, right?
Subtract the two values, and then you
had to plug it into the density equation,
so mass divided by that density.
Delta V or change in volume.
That's two steps.
So most of the math problems
are no more than that.
So if at this time you've been doing,
you've all been doing conversions that
have been like three or more steps for
most of the homeworks, and if you were
able to get through those, you should
have no problem getting through a one or
two step problem, which is Pretty nice.
So if you, the way that I treat my
tests is can you do the fundamentals?
If you can do the basics,
then you will get an A.
That's, you should get an A.
There's no reason really you
shouldn't, as long as you know
those key, those core concepts, like
can you do the basic conversions?
Can you do a simple swap drop?
Can you Tell me how many
valence electrons there are.
Can you like do these
little simpler questions?
A lot of the times it's nothing.
Are we going to have an
empty periodic table?
Oh my God, that sounds horrendous.
What do you mean?
Like literally just blocks
and then nothing in it.
That's a good idea.
Sure.
No, I'm kidding.
That's all I'm doing.
Um, that's what I had to
do when I was a chem major.
Like we had to fill out our periodic
table at one point, like from.
Just the blocks, um, so I had to memorize
the thing at one point in time, and
that's including the mass numbers.
Um, I forgot probably 90 percent of it,
um, but no, I'll give you the yellow
sheet, so you don't have to do that.
Can we go over how to create formulas?
Absolutely, we can do that too.
Let me, um, start writing down some
of the things that you guys want
to talk about so I don't forget.
Um, yeah, and if any point you guys
have topics that you guys want to
go over, I'll, I'll start writing
'em down so that way we have it.
We had homework four, question
five, and then we had do formulas.
Lemme hear my voice The worst
Okay.
All right.
It's crazy.
Well, it wasn't okay.
I shouldn't say it was the entire thing.
It was like the first.
Four rows.
First four or five rows.
Can we go over unit conversions?
Yes, absolutely.
So, we have kind of two options.
So, it's kind of up to you guys.
Obviously, if you don't
want to, we don't have to.
Um, so I could always poll, do a poll
to see what you guys are interested in.
Um, I do have a Kahoot that maybe some of
you clicked on already in the exam review,
which I think Kahoots are fun because it's
something you guys can play as a game.
Um, and I, and I made one of
another old exam into a Kahoot,
so it's a multiple choice thing.
I'm going to do a Kahoot.
Sure, we can do a Kahoot if more
people want to do it, that's fine.
So I made one of my old tests into
a Kahoot, which could, which will
go over, Pretty much, I would say
all of all these topics so far.
I don't remember what question
five on homework four is.
So let me pull that up real quick.
And then is there any, um,
Other things is a coot so much.
I mean, it is an old test, so I don't
know how much similar I can get.
Just keep in mind.
You know, I can give you practice
tests, it doesn't mean they're going
to be the exact same questions.
It's just showing you what
I've tested in the past.
It could be different, it
could be the same, it could be
just maybe different numbers.
It's, that is possible.
There's only so many things I can ask you.
Realistically, um, one of the things
you realize in homework is a lot
of times it starts repeating the
same problems, it's just different
numbers are going backwards.
So keep that in mind, there's a limit
to how much is possible to be asked.
So while you guys are thinking of
topics, oh, I see what question five is.
Um, I don't know if that's on the test.
I don't know if I put any that on there.
So it's like the pure element pure
compound mixtures and stuff like that.
I don't mind going over it, but I don't
know if I did put it on the test or not.
I can't remember.
Okay, so it looks like if, um,
let's say a couple of people
were okay with the Kahoot.
So let me pull that up.
Um, so, and then we can do it.
And then as we go through problems, like
the way that I do my Kahoot, it's not just
you guys just playing, seeing how they go.
Um, Um, after every problem, if
I see like, clearly there's a
lot of people that aren't getting
stuff, I'll switch to my tablet.
I'll kind of write it almost like as
if it's like a normal YouTube video and
we'll go through it and how to do it.
Okay.
So, um, you know, don't think I
won't take this and escape, escape.
Um, and when we're kind of going to
cat ion, anion, Bohr
model and Word problems?
I'm gonna need my word models.
I'm just gonna need word problems.
Um, word problems, yeah, sure could.
Word problems, yes, that could be a thing.
Um, in terms of would there be
anything with the bore model?
It's kind of, it's actually kind
of hard to do something with
the bore model on the exam just
because it's something that like,
In order to put it as a multiple choice,
it would have to be like, kind of like my
videos where I would show you something,
you gotta tell me how many electrons.
I actually really don't
do many Bohr model things.
The reason is, is because it's
the starting point, right, of
how to look at the electrons.
So it's more on electron configuration,
um, how to count valence electrons, and
I think there's one orbital diagram.
Problem, I think I ended up on there
and it's like still in the same vein.
It's like, okay, here's orbitals
Can you tell me which one's
correct or can you tell me?
Which element is it's right if you
see all the arrows Can you could you
be able to tell me if I give you the
orbitals and I give you the arrows?
Could you tell me what it is?
So that like that kind of problem you got
to remember it has to be multiple choice.
It can't be something that
You gotta draw, right?
So keep that in mind too.
I don't usually try to hide.
Like, when I was a student, I was
very similar to you guys when I first
did chemistry for the first time.
Oh my god.
I'm actually kind of surprised.
When I talk to a lot of people
that I was friends with at
that time, they're shocked.
that this is what I teach.
Like, cause we, it was tough.
Um, the teacher that I had it with, she
was a first, you know, bless her heart.
She was a wonderful person, but
it was her first time teaching it.
And she didn't really kind of know how
to teach in high school at the time.
So it was kind of a mess.
And yeah, there's a lot,
especially how much math there is.
It's, it's The math is the hardest part.
And for a lot of you, you guys
haven't seen the algebra probably
in years for many of you.
So that doesn't help at all.
Um, so it's, it's tough, but it's doable.
It is doable.
You guys got to remember that, you know,
I wouldn't, I, I know what I would tell
you, I would tell you if I'm like, Oh,
I mean, when we do this game and I see
like how the results are, I'll tell you
if I'm like, I'm nervous, I'll be honest,
but I you guys are capable of doing it.
You got it.
You have to believe that, though.
I can tell you all day
that and I do believe it.
But you have to do right at
any point when I start this
thing, you can join at any time.
So if you get kicked out to the
internet or whatever, um, You
know, you can always rejoin.
Uh, just keep in mind that, you know,
might, might make you do a new profile if
you have to connect to a different device.
So if your device is at, like, 10%,
you know, probably pick another one.
You know, pick an iPad or something or, I
don't know, do it on your TV or something.
Alright, here, let's start it.
I think this goes in
order of my Last test.
Well, I guess we're
starting with double points.
We're off the rip.
All right, so the correct scientific
notation for the following number is what?
So one of the things you have
to do is scientific notation.
And when you kind of do these
problems too, you can try
practicing counting your sig figs.
You can, as well, it's never a bad
idea to see if you can get just Yes,
and you can always look it up, you
know, if you want to check your answer,
um, and then why you're doing this
review too, you're welcome to use
your notes, obviously, but if you
want to, um, treat it like it's the
test, then don't, don't use them.
See how you do, you know, be honest with
it and see how many people signed up.
So I'm gonna, we'll kind of
let, uh, see how the timer goes.
I know it was at least 13 or 14 people.
Okay, good.
Okay, most of you guys got
this one, which is good.
So with this one, so it looks like
mainly people were stuck between
two different camps with this one.
So the first thing is, is making sure with
scientific notation, the biggest thing is
that it has to show your correct sig figs.
Meaning, that's kind of the beauty
of scientific notation, is that
it should show you the same number
of sig figs as the number did.
So, Being that it, when
we're counting this thing and
looking at the value, right?
When we start counting significant
values, we started at the five, then
we count the sandwich zero, right?
So that'd be two and two
would be the third value.
Then one, then we have a trailing zero.
Now that's where everybody is
usually like, is it significant?
Is it not?
Well, it depends if you
have a decimal value.
than it is.
In this case, it's a very tiny number,
there is a decimal, so therefore
it is significant in this case.
Okay, so it's one thing to
kind of pay attention to.
So we should have five sig figs, so
that's why, um, for the person that
picked yellow, you were really close,
but make sure you have that extra zero.
And then for the people that
picked red, So when it's small,
right, it's 10 to the minus 4.
So one trick that I taught myself
for how to know if I ever do these
right, is plug your scientific
notation answer, plug it into your
calculator and see what you get back.
You should get the same
decimal value, right?
So meaning, like, if you, if
everybody right now plugs in 5.
021 times 10 to the negative
4 into their calculator, They
should get a decimal value back.
And that's like a trick to
use your calculator, which
you have at all times, right?
You, you have that door in a test.
So it's like a, I don't know if it's
feeling it's cheating, but it's,
I think it's using your resources.
It's what you're allowed to have.
So, it's a trick.
And the same thing even
with the big number.
If you put 5.
021 times 10 to the 4, you'll
see that it's like 50, 210.
So, it's a lot larger
than the original number.
So, on the exam, what is
on the reference sheet?
It is the yellow sheet.
So, it is everything on the yellow
sheet except for the um, constants.
You don't need, you don't
need them on the test.
That's why.
Okay.
So this is actually Monday, Wednesday,
you guys did this this week.
So, um, you guys did a lab with this.
So suppose a thermometer marks at
every one degree increment and the
mercury level in the thermometer is
exactly between 25 and 26 degrees.
How should you report the measurement?
So keep in mind measurements are
they're not just important just for this
test, but really for the lab practical
at the end of the semester, right?
A lot of people forget that you
do have to know your lab skills.
Um, it's one of our agreements with
the nursing program, rad tech, dental
hygiene and respiratory therapy is
that you have to know your lab skills
prior to being allowed in this program.
So I need this class with a C or
above, um, is because your lab skills.
So knowing the basic measurements is key.
Okay, so with this one, so how
do you estimate digits, right?
So it said that the marks, so you
go off those tick marks, and it
said the tick marks are 25 and 26.
So that means that they're
every one essentially.
Now when you probably see the
actual thing, it'd probably be a
little easier because you see like
25, 26, 27, 28, and so on, right?
Um, so you always estimate one
past whatever the tick mark is.
So being that you see those single
digit numbers, that means you do
one decimal place in this case.
So it'd be 25.
5.
Um, for the people that picked
red, uh, how would you see that?
That's kind of like our grad cylinders.
Um, the values are every 0.
1.
So you'll see, like, it'll go from
the, and this is talking about the
10 milliliter grad cylinders, not
the a hundred, um, the 10 milliliter
grad cylinders, you'll see it goes
between one and two, but there's
10 lines in between one and two.
Um, so that's when you go that extra
spot and, uh, just so everybody knows.
So for, you know, for later, I
mentioned that there's a team assessment
after the exam, which is kind of
like a test, but it's low stakes.
You get your notes on that.
So that's the thing afterwards.
So bring your note, make sure you do
bring your notes to your exam day.
Um, And one of the things that I'll
have in that room when you do this
team assessment is that there'll be
some stations that could be like this
where there might be a thermometer in
front of you and you just got to tell
me what's the reported value so when
you write down your answer, um, so,
you know, could be a free question on
there that I can tell you that there
probably will be a thermometer of one or
a volume thing or something like that.
There are exactly 2.
54 centimeters in one inch.
When using this conversion factor,
how many sig figs are you limited to?
I got my, I got my editing cut
out for this video in between all
these sections with no talking.
All right.
So with this one, so what
do we think the answer is?
I'm assuming we're probably
waiting for that last person.
So you got four seconds to put
your answer in and lock it in.
Okay.
So we were between six
and 10 for number three.
Ooh.
So Why is the blue one right,
or the teal blue one right, and
not the people who picked three?
Because honestly, it looks like three, 2.
54 is three sig figs.
So why is it exact?
Well, if you look at your yellow sheet,
and you look next to that conversion,
it does say the word exact next to it.
And, you are converting into inches,
you're right, so you would think that
doing centimeters to inches, you should do
the sig figs, and usually you're correct.
But, there's only two conversions, I
believe, that are on that sheet, from
US to metric, that do have the words
exact next to them, which means that
there are an infinite number of sig figs.
And they don't affect your numbers.
And that's because
that's a measured value.
It's a perfectly No, I shouldn't
say it's a measured value.
It's a perfectly converted unit so
the systems can be bridged somewhere.
So then that's one of them.
I think the other one's
in joules, I believe.
I think it's like one of the joule
conversions is the other one.
But we don't really see
that one in this class.
So it's only, it's only this one.
I just wanted to kind of see
like, Hey, do you know what that
exact means whenever you see it?
So you ever see the word exact
that's telling you, Hey, this
is, no, this is the value.
So you can report the sig
figs however you want.
It does not affect your final answer.
Your measurements do.
Not this conversion.
How many low, that should say dose.
Sorry, typos are real.
How many low dose 81 milligram
Aspirin tablets can be used from 1.
21 kilograms of aspirin.
So, a lot of you guys are interested
in doing, you know, all the nursing
stuff, so it's a little conversion one.
And we'll do this one
together, so, afterwards.
When you're kind of doing the tests
too, so you might have saw I put
a longer timer on this one, right?
Um, you know, some problems, the
math ones, obviously will take
you a little bit longer to do.
Um, But when it comes to the, um, the
theory questions, you know, maybe on just
counting electrons or whatever simple
things, hopefully you get those ones in
like a minute or 30 seconds or something,
because hopefully you just kind of know
it, um, or how to do it right away.
So it's okay if this
one's taking more time.
It's balanced.
I try to balance it so
that way it's doable.
So, um, so we are doing
our first question.
So we have question number four.
So it's one you guys were just looking at.
So it says, how many low
dose, uh, 81 milligram aspirin
tablets can be used in this one?
So the first thing that I do whenever
I look at any of these, right, is I
highlight all the numbers I'm giving, or
I underline them, or, you know, whatever,
and you can have multiple pen colors if
you want on your desk, if it's something
that you do as well, I don't mind.
So, I got one here, I have the 1.
the aspirin.
I have 81 milligram
aspirin tablets as well.
So I got two things here.
Now the tricky part with this one is
probably kind of the way I kind of wrote
the question isn't maybe the most obvious
in terms of what conversion factors
exist here and what's really by itself.
So.
When you're kind of looking through
these, you got to define what
the different numbers represent.
So we have 1.
2 kilograms or two, one
kilograms of aspirin.
And then you also have how many, how many,
how big the tablets are, which whenever
you're talking about tablets, that is
a conversion because it's referring
to like 81 milligrams in a tablet.
If you look on any bottle of aspirin or,
or any type of, uh, You know, drug in
your medicine cabinet, their milligrams
per tablet is how they're defined.
So when you use that word per that's
telling you, Hey, this is a conversion.
I should word that I should have
worded this problem where it had that.
So it defines it, which is
something I made sure that
that was the case on the test.
So don't, don't worry about that
if there's something like this.
So when we're doing these, we always
start with the thing by itself.
The other one is 81 milligrams per
tablet is the other conversion.
Right?
Because you're trying to figure
out how many tablets are there.
So that's where, you know, the,
where that tablet part comes from.
So the thing is you need to do is we
need to be able to cancel our units.
We got to let the units
kind of guide our thinking.
Yeah, it is a tricky,
it is kind of tricky.
It's kind of the way it's worded
though, to be honest, it's not like I
said, it's not the best worded problem.
So how, what can we cancel?
So do we have any matching.
Types of units that you see do is there
anything that's matching and the one
thing that hopefully you're kind of
saying to yourself Or maybe you're trying
to frantically type is The grams right
so that's showing you hey, there is a
bridge here Can you define it right and
that's where you got to use your yellow
sheet to do that So when you're going
through that you have two options You
can either go straight from kilograms to
milligrams, which if you're really good
at unit conversions Transcribed Go ahead.
You can do that in one step.
Most of us though, including
myself, I like to make it a little.
easier by doing two steps, meaning
that I go from kilograms, then I go to
the base unit grams in this case, and
then I go out to the next prefix, I
always go to the base unit first, and
then I go back to wherever, because
that's what's defined on your sheet.
That's what you know, it's what you've
been practicing all along, like stick to
what you know, don't try something fancy.
Unless you don't know what to do,
then okay, sure, try something fancy.
But ideally, you Stick to what you know.
All right.
So the first thing is, is if
we have one kilogram, how many
grams are in one kilogram?
Can anyone tell me what do we got?
These are hopefully things
you kind of just maybe know.
I don't know.
Hopefully.
I know it's back to the zoom days.
No one wants to type anything.
Oh God.
It's really, we're
living the pandemic here.
So if you have one kilogram,
we would have 1, 000 grams.
It's also late.
Are you guys, if you had class
too, so I don't blame you and work.
1, 000.
Thank you.
So you have 1, 000 grams and one kilogram.
Right now, from there, we
want to go to milligrams.
So if we do that, one gram is
equivalent to 1, 000 milligrams.
Okay, great.
So does it all cancel so far?
Well, we can see kilograms
cancels kilograms.
Awesome.
And then we got grams cancels grams.
So our units are guiding our thinking.
That's the goal, right?
Can you set them up so that
way they always cancel?
Are they opposite of
each other is the idea.
Now, how can I now
integrate the tablet thing?
Well, I had this conversion from
earlier, which was milligrams per tablet.
So if I set it up to let my units
once again, guide my process.
So if I want to cancel milligrams, it
needs to be opposite in order to do that.
So if we do that, right, 81 milligrams
is on the bottom, we'll see that being
that they are opposite of each other.
Let's use another color.
They are opposite, they will cancel.
So we can then put tablet on the
top and then carry out our math.
And we should get our answer
that we have a, a absolute ton of
tablets when you go through this.
So how do you do the math?
Just sort of a review in case you've
been lost on this for four weeks.
You always multiply what's on top
and then you divide what's on bottom.
So we would do 1.
21 times a thousand times a thousand.
Hit the equal button on your calculator,
divide by 81, and you'll have your
answer, which in this case was, um, 1.
5 times 10 to the fourth power.
So it's done in two sig figs because of
the, um, 81 milligrams is two sig figs.
So if you picked dark blue,
then you got a correct.
So that's how you do that problem.
So this one is probably like on the.
Uh, this would be considered like the hard
dimensional analysis problem if it were
B on this test, it's arguably you could
say it's two steps just because it's going
still in the, the, the first two steps
are kind of, you can put them together.
But it would, this would be like, if you'd
probably get like one of something like
this, not, maybe not this problem, but one
of something like in this realm, right?
Of, of conversions.
Okay.
Let's, uh, go back to the thing.
And if anyone has any questions too,
so I can always answer them too.
So keep that mind while I
try to bring this back up.
All right.
So for the next one.
So this one's more of a one we
covered for Monday, Wednesday, we
covered it on Monday or Saturday.
last week's last video, if I
recall is the number for that one.
So, okay.
We were between the two
sides of the PR table.
All right.
So that's good.
When it comes to these
kinds of questions, right?
You want to, you're looking for
the extremes in terms of position.
So I'm happy that people were getting
down to that because it's when you start
kind of picking things in the middle, that
just tells me you have no idea, right?
At least you're kind of
using your reasoning.
So what does ionization energy mean?
So let's talk about that
definition for a second.
Ionization energy is how much
energy is needed to remove,
remove, right, an electron.
So what thing is out of the, out of
the two that were chosen, right, you
guys chose sodium and fluorine, which
one of them has a positive charge?
So thinking of that, right, one
of them has, it has a tendency
to have a positive charge.
Which means that it's really
easy to remove that electron,
is what that tells you, right?
So sodium, right, anything on the
left hand side of the periodic
table, has a very low ionization
energy, um, for the most part.
Except for hydrogen,
hydrogen's pretty high.
But all the metals, they have a very low
ionization energy, which is why they have
a tendency to be like, Sodium plus, or
cesium plus, or any, any, or potassium
plus, that's when they make those ions.
And the other thought process
is, think about the octet rule.
What's easier?
Is it easier for it to lose
the one electron, or for it
to gain the other electron?
seven electrons.
Gaining seven is pretty hard, right?
Can you find seven other atoms that are
willing to kind of give you a handout?
One way to look at it is like, is it
easier for you to give away 10 or convince
seven of your classmates to give you 10?
It's probably gonna be
a lot easier for you.
Someone's gonna take the
10 off you, no problem.
But to convince all your classmates
to give you that much money, it
might be a little tough, right?
And that's kind of the thought there.
It's a goofy analogy.
So fluorine really only needs one, so
it's not willing to lose those seven.
The other reason too is if you
think of the atomic radius trend, if
you remember as it went across the
periodic table to, towards fluorine
and the noble gases, it got smaller.
So being that it got smaller,
that means it's really hard to
rip those electrons away because
it's really close to the center.
So the, the two trends
are related to each other.
Um, if that helps, you know, if
you're, if you haven't really
studied it yet too, just kind of
maybe write down periodic trends.
So if you were to think
about a length, right?
So starting off the basic, cause you
got to derive the cubic conversion.
Well, if I have, let's say a line
and I were to define it, well, the
line, let's just say it's one meter.
Well, how many centimeters is one meter?
Well, when you look at your
periodic table, or not your periodic
table, your conversion sheet,
you'll see that it is a hundred
centimeters is in one meter, right?
So that's where the centi 100
comes from, but we want to cube it.
So what do we got to do?
We got to start to build.
Towards a cube.
So what's the first thing you do?
Well, let's say if you are measuring
a floor, right at the square
footage of something, let's say
it's a one meter by one meter box.
Well, then you'll have something
like that looks like this, right?
So it's 100 by 100.
So if we want to find the area, all
we have to do is say is I'm going
to take 100 centimeter times 100
centimeter And that's going to be the
equivalent to what one meter squared is.
So when we do that, all's we're going
to get is, uh, uh, 10, 000 centimeters
squared is equal to one meter squared.
But we don't care about squared.
We want to know about cube.
So what do I do?
Well, what we can do is we
can add a third dimension.
So we'll move our little conversions
here, and we will add the third
dimension by making it a cubic shape.
At least the best of my drawing
abilities, I'm the best artist, as
all of you guys see in my videos.
All right, we have our cube, right?
And so we'll add that third dimension,
right, which is another one.
So what are we going to do to what we
had before is we're going to multiply
it by another hundred centimeters.
And what you're going to get is you'll
have a million centimeter cubed is
equivalent to one meter times one meter
times one meter, which is one meter cubed.
So that's your conversion.
So that's what we're
going to use in this case.
So Now it doesn't have to be that long.
This is why I kind of don't put it
on there because it's really long
and usually you don't use it for
anything past the first two chapters,
um, but it's still kind of, it's
a good unit conversion practice.
It actually is probably
one of the best ones.
If I, if I were, I always tell students,
if you can do this conversion, you can
do any of them because I think this one,
in my opinion, is the hardest, I think.
That's why I don't put it in there.
I don't, I think it's hard.
So we'll just plug in our things, right?
So we had 1 meter cubed and
that's equivalent to 1 million
centimeter and then you just
multiply them So then you'd get 2.
5 times 10 to the 6th
power as your final answer
So that's kind of how you do it.
Um, and then you see your units cancel.
It's kind of hard but It's
only hard if you don't know
how to get the unit conversion.
You can do that for any of the units.
So whether it's meters,
centimeters, decimeters, whatever.
You can define it that way.
Okay.
So anyway, I'm sure that probably
bored everybody to tears.
But let's go to the next question.
So that was question six.
Alright, let's go on to another one.
Okay.
When an atom gains an electron, the
resulting particle is called what?
Right.
So this is the basic,
this is the real basic.
So hopefully, you know, this one,
um, this one's easier to probably
get it flipped between its other, its
counterpart, it's gaining an electron.
So that's the negative one.
So cation is positive.
Um, anion is, I think of onions cause
onions make you cry when you cut them.
So anion is, that would be that one.
Might've been misleading cause
I left it off the cation and
probably people clicked right away.
It was a finished talking about
it, but this would be a, the
anion would be the correct answer.
Which of the following is
a heterogeneous mixture?
So, oh, okay, never mind,
there it is, there they are.
Sorry, these are just words,
um, so you gotta kind of go off.
The different things that are here.
And like I said, if anyone has questions
about anything, please, please, please
type it in the chat at any point.
Don't be afraid to.
You can also direct message me too.
A lot of people have been
doing that, so it's fine.
Um, I, I don't, I won't be, I won't be
mad if you'd send it to me too, if you're
too afraid for 20 some people to read it.
And probably one of the things too is,
your question probably benefits everybody,
because everybody here wants to learn
and wants to do well on the test, so.
And if anybody's wondering, this is one
of those things that, you know, I've
been saying that I have a Excel sheet
that has what everybody does and goes
to like Grasp ETC and all those things.
The zoom reviews are one of those
things, by the way, reverse racing.
Oh no.
Oh no, I'm sorry, but I'm
looking at the yellow sheet.
I don't see how you got one
gram for 1, 000 milligrams.
Okay, that's actually
a really good question.
So the yellow sheet does the opposite
conversions that I usually use,
meaning that it's the flipped form.
So the yellow sheet does, um, 10 to the
negative 2 grams is equal to 1 centimeter.
So it's like the opposite of what that is.
So, oh boy.
All right, let's talk about this
and I'll talk about the conversion
thing that you asked me about.
All right, so with this one, oh
boy, I selected the wrong answer.
Oh, I selected the wrong one.
Oh boy.
Okay, so the right answer here It's
not air, that's definitely not air.
Air is a homogeneous mixture.
I clicked the wrong answer, so I
apologize for the people that didn't
get credit and that did, I guess.
So air is a homogeneous mixture.
Why?
Because you can't be able to, you can't
physically pick out the different pieces.
So in order for it to be
heterogeneous, it has to be something
that you can physically separate.
So.
If you were to go through those, so let's
say if you go through milk and not spoiled
milk, regular milk, you can't just easily
separate like all the fat and the water
and all those different things, right?
It's just this white liquid.
You really can't tell the difference
of all the different parts.
Sugar water.
So that's just like if you took a, if
you take like coffee and you put sugar
in it, And you, and you, and obviously
you stir it, do you see the sugar that's
in there, and usually no, you know,
obviously if it doesn't dissolve that's
another thing, but usually it dissolves,
so that would also be homogeneous.
Raisin Bran is referring to the cereal.
This is why I don't use this question
anymore, because I get like 10
students that I guess don't know
what Raisin Bran is, which is I
just, I figured Fresno has raisins.
I figured people would know
where raisins are and the cereal.
I was very wrong.
So Raisin Bran is a cereal.
It has raisins.
And then the cereal pieces and
um, that one is a heterogeneous
mixture because you can pick out
the raisins if you hate raisins.
So anyone that picked yellow
is picked the correct answer.
So I apologize if you chose yellow.
I can't give you points.
It's not my fault.
Well, it is my fault, but.
All right, let me talk about this yellow
sheet because this question has been asked
to me before and it's a really good one.
Um, so how essentially I was
asked, how did I get my unit
conversions from the yellow sheet?
It does not show the
same values that I have.
How does that, where am
I getting my values from?
And I do this in all my videos, all in
class too, is I'm always using essentially
my own version of the yellow sheet,
because I'm not a fan of the yellow
sheets conversions for small units.
I think they're confusing in my opinion.
Um, oh, I'll see you later.
Thank you.
But if you could go over question
five, all right, I'll try to put them
at the end of the review for you.
If worse comes worse, he can always
message me about it too later, , if
I forget, but I have it written
down in case I, in case I don't.
So, um, going back to
the, the yellow sheet.
So the way that the yellow sheet looks is
it has, it kind of has this written down.
It has centimeters, it has 10 to the
negative two next to it, um, as well.
So what exactly do those values represent?
What does that mean?
Well.
When we're kind of looking at those,
and I wish I had a yellow sheet near me.
I usually have like 30 of them
laying around my office and I don't.
I guess I could pull one up.
You know what, let me find one so that
way I can make sure I explain this.
Actually, wait, oh,
wait, hold on one second.
I can share it.
Give me a sec.
It works for centimeters cubed to meters
cubed, which is probably the most common
one that you would ever have to use.
Okay, so here's the,
here's the yellow sheet.
Sorry, it's not yellow.
It's my, it's white for me, but
this is the original version.
Um, So when you're looking at this thing,
we were using the following conversions.
We were using Senti and we were also,
well, we'll just focus on that one.
So let's say we're using Senti.
So the way to read this thing
to make sure you're using it
correctly, if you don't want to use
my version, you can use this one.
The way that all these represent
is the right hand column.
So everything that's, um, over here,
I'm highlighting in red real quick.
This represents what
the base unit value is.
So I'm gonna write below
it, this is the base unit.
And what do I mean by the base unit?
This could refer to as grams, liters,
Celsius, joules, any type of unit
that can have a prefix in front of it.
So the big ones that we've been using
in class a lot are really grams,
liters, and eventually we're gonna start
using kelvin and joules a lot more.
So those are kind of the most.
common ones for now that I can think of.
I'll tell my head.
Um, and so I guess there's
seconds too, right?
But, uh, you know, there's no
time conversions on this test.
It's mainly what you kind of
applying to lab is what I focus on.
Um, So if we were to read this,
everything that's on the left hand
side, these are all referred to as just
being one of whatever that value is.
So if you were to read this, it
means that you have one centimeter
for every 10 to the negative two
grams, which is the opposite of
what, how I describe it, right?
The one way that I look at it.
So if you were to write
that as a fraction.
I flip the fraction, or I flip the
numbers, where I say that if I have
100 centimeters is 1 gram, which if
I rewrite that, that's 10 to the 2
is what that's equivalent to, right?
So I flip my numbers because
it's a fraction trick.
You can do that.
And when you have a larger number,
I find that students are less likely
to make errors if they don't have
to put decimals in their calculator.
So it's one of the reasons
why I personally use it.
Um, and if you don't believe me, one
thing you can do for yourself is if you
grab a calculator and you do one divided
by point, uh, or 10 to the negative two,
and you tell me what answer comes out.
So do, do this math conversion here.
The one that's, uh, Blinking right now.
Put that in your calculator.
What number do you get?
So do 1 divided by 10 to the negative
2 and tell me what value you get.
And you're gonna see why
this, this makes sense.
Because it's a ratio.
You get a hundred, which is the
value that I use for centimeters.
So 100 centimeters is 1 gram.
It's the right, it's a ratio.
It could be any, as long as the ratio
is the same, you can use whatever
numbers you want realistically, as
long as the ratio is 100 to 1, right?
So this, what's on the bottom, it
does show 100 to 1, but it's dividing
by the, by that value in this case.
Um, so it's just another
way of looking at it.
So if you want to use just your
yellow sheet, then you would
define your conversions like this.
So just to show another one, like if
you had, um, one kilometer, that's
equal to 10 to the three meters.
Um, being that it's 10 to the 3 up here.
Or if you had one nanometer, that
would be 10 to the negative 9.
meters.
So you're just kind of
defining based off that.
So it's another way to do it.
You can use that.
I'm, I don't, you can choose
whichever one you want.
I, I liked, I personally prefer to
always use big numbers because I
find that usually you guys do better.
And then I always stick to what people
do better with, you know, I'm always
going to do what helps my students.
There's a reason why that I make
you guys do all the things you do.
It's because I found that it's,
it's made big, big impacts.
So it's good things, right?
Better grades are more happier
students and more of you pass.
Let's keep going.
All right.
So hopefully that answered
your question there.
All right.
So I'm going back to this guy over here.
And if like I said, if there's any
other questions anyone has, yeah.
And keep in mind for this
question here, right?
You Won't have the white periodic
table for those of you guys who have.
Oh, well, everybody probably
has one at this point.
But if, um, so your yellow one
won't have the charge written.
When you get it, you are welcome to brain
dump whatever you want on that thing.
I don't care.
That's fine, but it has
to be like in your head.
And there is always a periodic
table in the lab too that you can
always look at as well if it helps.
The one on the wall.
Don't forget that exists.
If it helps, I don't know
why it would help more.
Other than that, it has the Roman
numerals for valence electrons on it.
So where I'm a little confused is how
do you know it will convert to grams?
Does that make sense?
So are you talking about
if you kind of like have
Let's say you're doing
a prefix conversion.
How do you know if you
need to go to grams first?
Like that kind of question
is what you're asking?
Like how, how did I decide to go
to grams and then go to the prefix?
Because that's what I think you're
asking, but I wanted to clarify.
Okay, good.
How are you?
It looks like almost
everybody got this one, right?
So it's on the second column.
So, um, that would be a two plus charge.
Nice.
Yeah, if, if it's the question
I think you're asking.
So when I go to grams or convert
to the middle of the prefixes, I
do it whenever I have to usually
go from a prefix to a prefix.
Um, being that the table, it's
all in reference to the base unit.
It doesn't give you the
differences between prefixes.
So what I mean is if you had to go from
centi to micro, Well, you can do the math
and do that conversion, but what I see
is most students are not comfortable or
confident in their math skills to do that.
So usually what I say is, is you take,
go to set, take Senti, you go to,
let's say whatever your base unit.
So let's say is centimeters.
You go to meters, and then you convert
back to micrometers and involves
an extra step that allows you to
use your reference sheet as like a
crutch to get yourself through it.
So that way you get the correct answer.
Um, being that, you know, it's no secret
at this point, you can, you, you have
references all around you, you has when
you even when you're working and doing
these things, but You have computers,
you have your phone, you have resources.
Obviously you want to, you got to be
able to know how to use them correctly.
That's the thing is why you still
have to take classes and can't
just have AI doing it for you.
Cause that's how someone's
going to get killed one day.
You know, you got to, you got to
have the brain power to be able to
recognize those things is what I
always say is you got to be able to
think critically, think through it.
So the way that I critically think
through it is I go to that base unit
because I can use my reference sheet
and then I go back out to whatever unit.
Okay.
So it's that's how you know when it's
whenever it's gonna be I think from prefix
to prefix is how I know Today I think is
how when I go to the the middle step But
you don't have to you could just skip it
and those students I see need it Probably,
I would say 85 percent of people need it.
Identify the element that is a
non, should say metal, not mental,
non metal gas and has a symbol
that starts with the letter A.
So what that means is you got
to know how to kind of use your
periodic table, so that way you
know where the different areas are,
and kind of know how it's
sort of organized here.
If you're not sure how to do this one,
What's vital is, so you should be able
to see the answers on your device.
So let me share my tablet so I can
share the search trick to memorize
the elements in the periodic table.
You don't have to memorize all of them.
I always tell students, I think it's wise
to measure or to memorize the first 20.
And the reason I say that is because
it's for all the nursing people mainly.
Most of those first 20 elements
are your essential minerals.
So I think like 11 of the 20
So like potassium, sodium,
magnesium, all these things that,
you know, are vital to your health.
So when you have to take
nutrition, knowing about those
essential minerals is, is helpful.
So in order to memorize them, really
for me, what was my trick is I, I
just put the, I put the name on one
side and then the symbol on the other.
Um, you can put the atomic number
if you want on there, but, and I
guess that helps, I would say, but
you don't need to memorize the mass.
Like you'll always get the
periodic table for that.
But.
I would think that the the name and the
symbol or I would say are good starts
if the atomic number is It's not bad
to know it, but you could get away
with not knowing that it just kind of
depends on you But I think flashcards
that's what I would do You know, you
get a hundred pack of flashcards at
the dollar store or at the bookstore I
think at the bookstore they're like two
bucks, I think, or something like that.
And that's usually what I did.
Um, or if you're someone that's
like, Oh, I don't want to buy
flashcards, you probably can Google
like, periodic table flashcards.
And I guarantee you, there's probably
something I wouldn't be surprised if I
put periodic table flashcards at some
point in one of the modules at this point.
Um, being that, uh, you know,
I always am putting different
study references in places.
All right, so how to do this
one looks like almost everybody
got it, which is fantastic.
So what do you what do you do?
So the first thing is, is for you guys,
the zigzag is not in red, it's black.
So that zigzag line, what that
represents, it's the boundary
between non metals and metals.
Right?
So non metals is on the
right, metals is on the left.
Now, the more right you get on
the periodic table, the more
likely you're going to find a gas.
So the one thing area you
definitely know are gases, right?
The noble gases are all gases, right?
So that's kind of the area
for certain are all gases.
After that, it's like these guys here,
the halogens are typically gases.
The one that's kind of
hit or miss is bromine.
That's, that's usually a liquid.
It just depends on the temperature.
Um, but the noble gases,
it's in their name, right?
So knowing those names mean we've done
so much electron configuration, right?
So hopefully that kind of rings home.
So if you're looking at that, right,
you can see which Noble Gas has a in
its name, and that would be argon.
So that I, I would hope
that that's the choice.
That is, it could.
I was like, well, God, hopefully I
didn't lead you guys on a tangent without
checking the answer, and it's fun.
Um.
Okay, and then I gotta ask the question.
I'm having trouble trying to decipher
whether we should use sigfig,
scientific notation, or write the
full decimal number for our answers.
Will the exam problems let
us know which we should use?
That's a loaded question.
Um, much more loaded
than you realize it is.
My answer usually always is, is you
want to round it to the correct sigfigs.
is usually the answer I'll stick by.
Um, when it comes to when do you need
to know if it's scientific notation, it
usually is whenever it's a very, very
large number or a very, very small number.
Or let's say you're rounding the
value and you could not illustrate
the correct number sig figs with
your, um, with your rounded value.
So what do I mean by that?
So, uh, one of you in lab
today had to round, it was like
something kind of like this.
It might've been actually, it might've
been Melanie, it might've been her number.
She had like this number,
which was, uh, 10, 049 joules.
And she had around a two, two sig figs.
Well, how can you actually
go and try to round that?
Well, two sig figs means that
you gotta round it to this spot.
So, what's the issue here is, well, okay,
well I can round that, not a problem.
But when you do that, right, four
is you round down, so it's gonna
be 1, 000 is gonna be your answer.
That's not wrong, but the thing is, you're
not illustrating the sig figs correctly,
so you're actually losing sig figs.
Because this one only shows
one sig fig, you need two.
So the only way to show that correctly
is using scientific notation because when
you put this in scientific notation So
we say 1 2 3 or so when I say 1 point 0
times 10 to the 3 Now I'm telling people
that this 0 is significant, but it was
rounded So I couldn't actually, you know
illustrate that with the original number.
So it's always based on
It's kind of your judgment.
A lot of the times it always should
be rounded to the correct sig figs.
There are some homework questions that
do tell you to do the full decimal
value, and then it in the next question,
it'll tell you to round it, but.
You always want to round, the only
time you usually don't round right
away is let's say if you're doing lab
calculations, you might put your whole
decimal value and then at the very,
very end when you're finished your
calculation, then you round at the end.
So you want to wait until
like the very last step.
It's like what we said with multiple step
operations, wait till the end to round.
Um, if hopefully I answered it.
Okay, then, Audrey asked, uh, can we
go over how to know what ions are in a
random compound and its chemical formula?
Example, aluminum dichromate,
uh, oh, you're welcome.
Uh, are in a random compound
and its chemical formula.
Oh, so you're asking like, Are
you asking, like, how to know?
I'm asking about, like,
the Rowling compound.
Sorry.
Yeah, you're okay.
I was like, oh my god, a voice.
You scared the heck out of me.
Go ahead.
It's okay.
I just want to keep typing.
No, you're good.
What was yours?
Say it again.
Um, it's, like, the Rowling
compound homework we have.
At the end, you have a start
with, like, the Oh, man.
Word and then like find out
what the cation formula.
Okay.
I got you.
I forgot about that's
what you're referring to.
Okay, that's perfect Thank you for
which assignment right so that one so
you were saying aluminum dichromate
So that's a great example to use
so this one kind of comes with I
guess a few things.
It's knowing your how to use your
reference material and a little bit
of some memorization, too I guess
because you know, for example What
I mean by memorization is like
knowing aluminum's charge for example
knowing the cation on that Just
because that's part of the steps.
You kind of got to know that charge
I mean, it's on the third column so
you can kind of know it but you know
Dichromate is one of your polyatomics.
So knowing that one too relies on
using the green sheet Um On the exam,
in terms of knowing names, I believe
there's only, I think there's only one,
pretty sure it's just one, maybe there's
two, but I think it's one, and it's
not a, if it is a poly, if it is the
polyatomic one, like I said, it's going
to be an oxyanion, it's not going to be
like dichromate, which is one of those
bottom ones, that's a little harder.
So when you're going through
this, just kind of talk about it.
So the first thing you want to do
is you got to identify, you had to
identify the cation and the anion.
So cation is always written
first, anion is always written
second, always, no matter what.
So aluminum, right, has a
three plus charge, right?
So it's always that
charge, no matter what.
Afterwards, you had to find what
chromate's charge is, right?
So that's when you got to
use your reference material.
Whenever you don't see it in that's
one of the reasons I say like you maybe
watch the t4 three video so that way
you can Know your poly your your your
eight polyatomics because it helps limit
your search That's the big idea when
you have All these reference materials.
It is so overwhelming.
The amount of information you've
been given over the last five
weeks, at least I think so.
If you guys don't agree,
then God, you're amazing.
But most people think that, right?
It's a lot.
And that's okay.
But, um, If you start memorizing portions,
it eliminates a good chunk of your search.
That's why I say memorize
the first 20 elements.
Know the T4 3 method or whatever to
memorize that top part of the polyatomics.
Um, so that way it's one
less thing to look at.
So dichromates at the very
bottom of the green sheet.
Um, hopefully I'm getting this one right.
I think it's C2 07 and
it's Two minus charge?
Is it two minus?
I don't have my green
sheet in front of me.
Anyone confirm that it's two minus?
I don't, we don't, I don't use
dichromate a lot for examples.
Does anyone know what charge it is?
I know it's C2O7 though,
because I'm pretty sure.
Unless I'm wrong.
It's a two minus.
Yes, got it right.
Yeah, I'm not, I'm not, I know things.
All right, so, C207, so, um, and
being that there's a couple of
people, so I'm going to log off.
Thank you so much for the help.
Oh, absolutely.
You're absolutely welcome.
Hopefully it helps.
I actually need to go.
I'm going to watch the recording tomorrow.
Yes.
My goal is to try to edit it down
so that way it's not as long.
Um, and then I'll, Probably
upload it to YouTube.
So we any of you can watch
it whenever you want.
Um, and then it's, you know, just
available throughout the whole semester.
So you have it for the final if
you want to rewatch any of it.
Um, so as long as it recorded
properly, if it has your names and
stuff in it, then I won't use it.
But I think I sent me it.
So it doesn't show any of them.
I hope we'll see.
We're still supposed to zoom link.
Okay.
Um, but going back to, um, So if,
um, so we gotta swap, drop it next.
So we have the cation
ion, we have 'em labeled.
Now you gotta swap drop.
So we have our three that's
gonna go outside the parentheses.
So that's gonna come down to the left.
And then the two is gonna
come over next to aluminum and
we will write that as well.
So what and when we rewrite that,
we'll have al two C 2 0 7 with a
three next to it and lemme clean
up that three 'cause that is bad.
Okay, there we go.
Oh, I'm frozen.
Oh, nevermind.
Less frozen.
Okay.
It's like maybe my internet
connection, I'm sure it's not
the best, but that's kind of how
you go through it step by step.
So define your ions, um, and then,
so let's kind of write that down.
So define ions, and that might require
a mixture of, um, uh, periodic table.
And then let's say if you don't know the
metal charge, then it's going to rely
on you finding the polyatomic, which is
always going to have the same charge.
So you got the, like we were doing
in class for Monday, Wednesday,
like we were just practicing all
the polyatomics, all the predictable
stuff with those variable charges.
So sometimes you gotta make sure
you know where to find them.
So the more you practice at the end,
easier it's going to be to find them.
That's why I started doing that
nomenclature game last, I want to say
last spring or fall I started doing
it, and it's been, a lot of your
naming in SwapDrop has gotten so much
better since I started doing that.
Most of you don't really struggle
with SwapDrop after that, so
that's the more important thing.
Naming is important too, but
it's the SwapDrop that's crucial.
Or, uh, when we do chemical formulas,
and how to do, um, balancing, and when
we do moles next week, or for, well,
Saturday's doing moles this week, but
Monday, Wednesday, when we do moles next
week, it'll, it makes a big difference.
Okay, so hopefully that
answers your question.
Um, for the parentheses, when
and when do we not use them?
Great question.
So when do you not use them, and when do
you, so you use them only for polyatomics.
And only if you had to swap
drop a subscript next to it.
So in this example, I had to
bring the three to say that I
have, uh, three dichromate ions.
The whole dichromate is a unit, right?
That whole polyatomic is one
whole thing that's connected.
So when you have to swap drop, so if
you had a swap drop and it's a one,
let's say you were bringing down,
um, so trying to, Let's maybe come
up with an example like that, uh,
Um, let's see, add sodium,
uh, carbonate for example.
So now we're gonna do this
one, right, it's carbonate
to 2 minus, sodium is a plus.
So when I swap drop those values,
right, and I bring them down to
each side, so I bring the 2 down
to sodium, I bring the 1 down to
carbonate, what is that gonna make?
Well, we'll have sodium, 2, CO3, And
then we'll have a one next to it.
But remember, one is not needed.
One of the things I like to
say is chemists are lazy.
If we don't have to write
it, we shouldn't write it.
So in that case, being as one, you
don't have to include the parentheses.
So we get rid of them.
It's only when you had a
swap drop a value next to it.
So if you include them, though, by
accident on the on the on any of the
homeworks, it will mark you incorrect,
though, because you don't need them.
It's only when you have a subscript.
So, if you're like, why am I getting
this wrong, I have the polytomies,
I swapped, dropped it, I did
everything right, it might be because
you include the split parentheses.
And you can always send me a
screenshot too on Discord or, you know,
Discord's always the easiest thing.
But if you send it to me on there, then
I can just be like, I'll tell you in
five seconds if it's if that's the issue.
Usually that's it.
Or maybe you forgot to reduce
the subscripts as well.
That's a big one too.
A lot of people have been doing that too.
Um, yeah, that would be MGF2.
Yep.
So for those ones you don't
need any, any parentheses.
So atoms, you don't need them.
It's only for polyatomics.
So MGF2.
Perfect.
So you just got to make sure
you put it as a subscript when
you type it into MyOpenMath.
Um, which of the following
is a pure substance?
All right.
So this was one of the things I was
asked about on, um, uh, homework number
four question Five was like how to
discuss if it's pure substance, is it
a mixture, all these kinds of things.
So, um, pure substance means that it's
only one element, or it's one compound.
So thinking about that, right?
So you guys mainly picked
between air and ice.
Air is a mixture of elements, right?
It's a mixture of the diatomic elements.
So it's nitrogen gas, oxygen gas.
You can argue that there's
other contaminants in there too,
obviously, but it's mainly nitrogen
and oxygen for the most part.
So that's where we consider a
mixture of diatomic elements.
Um, in terms of.
Ice, it's just water.
It's just frozen water.
So it's compounds.
So it's a pure compound, you
know, hopefully it's pure compound
Brass is a mixture of metals.
So it's like a almost a copper iron
and a couple other things together
Maybe some zinc all mixed together and
kind of doing things You're also dying
with the mini lectures too because
you got added a little late So you
got a little extra to do Actually,
you gotta catch up, that's hard.
And then seawater is salts, water, and
those mixed together and all that stuff.
Okay, uh, I was asked the question,
uh, Will the exam tell us when
to reduce the polyatomic or
should we automatically do it?
Do you mean like, uh, in terms
of reducing like the subscripts?
Like let's say if it was um, I don't
know, you swap dropped and it had
like, atom one had like a two, and
then atom, and then polyatomic.
Two had a two outside and you reduce them.
You should automatically
always reduce if you can.
Um, so it's whenever they're
commonly can be divided by the
same number, but make sure you
never touch the polyatomic itself.
As I, as one of the phrases
I say a lot with that one,
a polyatomic is like family.
They stay together, you
don't change the family.
So like, carbonate is always CO3,
you know, nitrate is always NO3.
Don't change that, only the
subscript outside the parentheses.
You can reduce that.
And it's, if it's like 2 and 2, reduce it.
2 and 4, reduce it.
If it's 4 and 8, you know, anything
that you can see that it can
be divided by a common thing.
So, um, This was a
question on your homework.
It goes over like, uh, Beyonds asked
about mixtures, elements, compounds.
What are you going to do?
So this is kind of one of them.
Um, or hanging out.
Oh, you're absolutely welcome.
Oh yeah, and you can, and if you,
if you want to do the Kahoot 2
on your own, it is posted in the
exam module just so you guys know.
So it is available.
Um, so, You what you're doing for
these is you're kind of like looking
at each thing that's given to you
and you're trying to see is Well,
what is it exactly as it's showing?
So for this one, right you have sodium
Hypochlorite is what's being shown to you.
So NaClO.
Oh, so you see three elements that
are bound together And it's the only
compound that's being listed here.
So you can make the assumption that it's
just one compound that's being shown.
So being that's the case, that means that
this is considered to be a pure compound.
Same with, like, the next one.
It's also just, like, one compound.
You can do the same thing.
The ones that are harder are these guys,
depending on which pictures you get.
So you're looking at those images that
like we've seen before that have gone
through any of the videos or in person.
Before I had them with just
black and white, uh, balls, at
least in my videos and stuff.
But these are, you're looking at, okay,
so the, we have these, uh, Two blue
orbs that are connected to each other.
So it's a diatomic.
It's the same element
that's connected together.
So this is referring to a diatomic.
So something like nitrogen, maybe
it would be a good guess like N2.
So what is that?
Well, It's not a mixture of
multiple elements because you would
need two different gases, right?
Like maybe a red ones and blue ones
or red and yellow something like that.
So this again is a pure element even
though they're bound together, but it's
just one element because this is the
natural form that the diatomics exist in.
Um, one of the things I say for remember
your diatomics have no fear of ice cold
beer and this is one of your diatomics.
So in that case, This one's
kind of the same idea.
It looks like it's the same ones,
but it's just a solid versus gas.
Um, this one, we didn't really
get a super good question.
I wonder if I could make
it, give me a different one.
Um, I guess I can on my version
once I submit it, but it's, uh,
my, there are other ones that
do have like different compounds
here that are all mixed together.
So you'll see multiple different things.
Are there any questions with
pictures on the, um, Team assessment.
There's some on the, uh, on the test.
I'm going to say, I don't think I put
any on the test on the team assessment.
Yes, because you have your notes.
So I thought that'd be a little
bit more manageable and you
can talk with your partner.
About it, too.
So I try to do like more thought provoking
things with your partner So that way
you have someone to also stress with
together and it's less crazy But like
I said the team assessment don't stress
over it one of the things too is like
don't worry about your grade until I
see them because usually the grades
are really low at first because Like
the auto grader doesn't grade them.
Well, so I got to like look through all
your your grades so Whatever grade you
get on the team part, don't freak out
this guy, give me time to look at them.
So that's another thing to warn
everybody, especially Saturday, because
you guys, I don't see, so I'm like,
I don't need you guys to accidentally
kill Professor Gilly because your grades
are like, it's like a 60 percent and
it's like, that's not the real thing.
I got to look at it.
It's probably like an 85 or 100.
I just got to look.
Um, so just so you know.
For that part,
uh, oh, and then density.
Yeah, we can talk about density.
Uh, I, it's going to be one of the
questions on the Kahoot though.
So we, I hopefully it comes up soon.
So you want to go through your process,
you know, um, one of the things that's
never a bad study tip, it kind of involves
a little bit of work, but you could always
kind of like define your own little,
um, uh, like how to guide for anything.
You don't have to, you always use mine.
It's what works for you.
Does someone have a question?
I heard a unmute and I'm scared.
I was like, am I going
to get scared again?
My voice coming from like, Oh, talking,
but all right.
So it looks like we kind of had some
people picked a couple different things.
So let's show it real quick.
Um, so with this one, uh, so you
want to look up the two charges.
So the first thing is like, if
you were to look up aluminum,
right, it's one of your steps.
So in this case, it would be a
three plus charge with that one.
So tablets slowly coming up.
There it goes.
So you'd have aluminum, right?
That's three plus.
It's a part of your steps, as
I kind of always say, right?
So it's kind of remind people,
what am I talking about?
So when it comes to the Piroc table,
there's like naturally steps in the
Piroc table that look like this.
So it's aluminum, zinc, silver.
And then they have the charges
plus one plus two plus three.
So it's first step, step,
second, step, third step.
That is like, it's helpful to remember it.
So we've got AL and you guys
probably know oxygen, right?
That's a two minus charge.
And now what you're going to do is
you're going to swap your numbers, right?
So the two is going to come down next
to aluminum, and then the three is
going to come down next to oxygen.
And then what you will get is you'll have
a L two, and then you're going to get.
Oxygen.
with a three next to it.
So it's just kind of showing, it's showing
that there's, there's numbers come down.
Aluminum still has a three plus charge.
So just keep that in mind.
It's just so that way the overall ionic
compound is neutral as the whole idea.
So to kind of like show that math, right?
You have, if you have
two aluminums, right?
They're three plus and three plus.
And then on the right hand side, we
have three oxygens that are 2 2 2
you see that they're each 6 on each
side, so it balances out and makes a
neutral compound, which is the goal.
It's lower energy, it's more
relaxed, it's more stable.
It's an easy one, right?
So your atomic number is what
you're looking at here for protons.
Um, you know, there's probably
going to be a question that
has to do with atomic number.
So knowing that, um, maybe calculating the
subatomic particles could be another thing
to, you know, make sure you're okay with
doing protons, neutrons, and electrons.
Um, this could be another one too, right?
So it says xenon is a
member of which family?
Which means which column.
So what's the name of that column?
We said it earlier too.
So I would recommend knowing the
two columns on the left side of the
periodic table and the two on the right.
Those are like the those are usually the
most common and then knowing transition
metals like just remember those names.
So like we're sodium and super lithium
and sodium are that's the alkali metals or
beryllium is that's the alkaline metals.
And then where fluorine is, is
halogens, and then the noble
gases for um, helium and down.
All right, the number of dots representing
valence electrons in the electron
dot structure of nitrogen is what?
Um, electron dot is the same thing
as the Lewis dot structures, by the
way, just so everybody knows that.
Wait, I just realized it doesn't even
give you the numbers for how many.
Okay, so feel free to type in
the chat what, how many dots
you would have around nitrogen.
The choices do not match this problem.
So feel free to pick whatever answer
you want on this one, because I actually
have no idea which one's the correct.
None of them make sense.
So just pick one.
It must have, it must not have
saved my choices because I was
like copying a previous problem
each time and then editing the.
values.
So, but try to figure out how
many dots there are though.
Still, we'll go over it.
Okay, so kind of how to do this.
So for any of these, so the biggest thing
that's important here is this is about
valence electrons more than anything.
And Audrey, perfect.
That's a perfect answer.
And same with, uh, Jocelyn too, perfect.
Um, so valence electrons, I can
guarantee you'll have to count
them on the test somewhere.
Um, so what do you got to do?
It's pretty easy once you
realize the trick behind it.
So the first thing you always do is, is
you want to find wherever the element
That you're looking for is right.
So we have nitrogen right here.
And what we do is after that
is we have to, if we count how
many S and P electrons, God,
I'm trying to erase this thing.
I hate that they changed that.
How many S and P electrons are in its,
in I guess it's highest quantum number.
It's its lowest row, if that's
how you want to look at it.
So if you remember, we could
number each row, right?
We have one, two, three,
four, five, six, and seven.
So we're in row two.
So we're going to count all of the S and
P electrons until we get to nitrogen.
So S is the first two columns, right?
So we have one, we have two, then
we have three, And we have four, and
then we get to nitrogen, that's five.
So that tells you you have
five valence electrons, a.
k.
a.
you have five dots when you
show the lowest dot structure.
So all we're going to do is,
we're going to go one, three,
It doesn't matter where the two
dots are, if you have on the left,
the top, the right, as long as you
have five dots and one of them is a
pair, then you got a perfect, right?
Um, which is the whole idea.
Usually I always start in the top and then
wrap around when I'm doing it personally.
But you know, you can, if you start on
the left or right, it doesn't matter.
I always get asked that so
far from here until then.
Good job guessing calcium
on that question, by the
way, for the random guests.
I don't know how that's correct, but.
Um, none of them are correct.
So good job.
Uh, whoever got whoever's yellow
or whoever got the yellow choice.
Okay.
So we got this one.
An atom containing seven protons,
eight neutrons, seven electrons is,
is what, how would you define it?
out of all these choices.
And this like is a thing to make
sure you're not trying to match
the atomic mass for an isotope
to the one on your Pirog table.
So this is for very specific isotopes,
so use the data that's given to you.
The only thing you can look up
realistically is um, What the elemental
symbol is if you were to try to write
out the notation so always use what's
given to you in the problem So if we
were to try to write this guy out The
biggest thing is that the only one that
was true here was that it was neutral
I don't think this is a bad time to go
over Making sure you guys are okay with
writing that atomic notation, right?
So, um, when we're kind of doing
this one, you had seven protons,
so that's gonna be nitrogen again.
So what we would end up writing is
nitrogen seven at the bottom for its, its
number, and then we had eight neutrons.
So it's eight plus seven for the mass.
So it's nitrogen 15 would be the value.
And you notice that doesn't
match your periodic table.
It's just a different isotope of it.
Remember, these are averages of all the
isotopes available for these species.
So, you know, don't don't automatically
assume like it cannot exist or something.
And for it to be an ion, the
electrons would have to be
different than the protons.
Perfect typo.
Um, what is the electron
configuration of aluminum?
So these ones are like really
tricky multiple choice.
This is one that I actually took
from an old final exam so When the
final when we get there, right?
It's a standardized test.
So it's like a studying for
So you're kind of looking at a mixture
of things, so you want to, one, see
if you can write it out for aluminum.
That's usually what I
recommend doing first.
I usually don't just look at the choices,
I always try to answer the problem
without looking at the multiple choice.
Um, the only time I look at
the multiple choice is if I
have no idea on how to do it.
Um, because you want to see if
you get your answer first and then
you check against what's there.
The other thing you're kind of noticing
with these is you need to pay attention
to like Anything that doesn't follow
the rules of electron configuration,
which okay, everybody got this one.
So here are the perks.
I don't even have to even explain it.
So you always want to make
sure that you check if there's
anything that violates rules.
Um, so what I mean by that is like,
if I think you look closely, like,
you see, like, C is three P eight,
for example, like, you can't have
more than six electrons in that one.
Um, I think there's like another one.
I thought that was wrong.
Maybe not.
It's all the same, same.
Okay.
Same.
I guess it only changes the 3p.
So you're kind of like looking at every
orbital sometimes to make sure there's
nothing like weird happening, like nothing
in the wrong orders, no electrons missing.
Like are any of the rules being violated?
That's one thing you want to check too.
All right.
Double points.
Uh, the number of electrons
in the outer energy level.
of a neutral atom of boron is what?
And I guess this one you could argue is
a Bohr model example, um, if you want to,
but you don't have to define it that way.
If you know your vocabulary, then
you know what this is referring to.
It's just wording it in
a scary sounding way.
We did, we did this problem
kind of already, but with dots.
We did it with nitrogen.
So with this one, What is it referring to?
So it's talking about the
outermost energy level.
So that's talking about
the valence electrons.
That's all it's asking you.
It's just kind of in a,
you know, scary worded way.
So one of the things I always tell
students is whenever you have word
problems, like this one wasn't that
long of a word problem, but always
try to See if you can find the most
important piece of information.
So like for this one, you know, it
says boron and then outer energy level.
So knowing valence is always
talking about the outer level.
So what's on that outside is the key here.
Um, so when you're doing that,
right, you count your S and P
and that second row for boron.
So it's going to be three.
This is the whole idea.
So you count lithium, beryllium, and
then boron, and that's how you get three.
It has five electrons, but it
has three valence electrons.
So three valence, two core electrons.
That's how to label them.
All right, which one is for carbon?
What's the correct way to write
it for the electron dot structure?
And like I said, this,
this was an old exam.
So if you feel like you've been doing
well on this so far, then, I mean,
then so far you've done at least
the basics and the beginning stuff
so far, which is, which is good.
Like I said, it's just your fundamentals.
Um, this is probably around the
same difficulty as the current one.
If I were to kind of label it, I think.
Maybe there might be, we haven't gone
over the last 10, so it might be same
level difficulty for the last ones too.
If you haven't known them, then, you
know, write down the topics and that's,
that's so now you know what to study.
That's, that's the idea.
You know, never, Never let it scare you.
It's just, okay, now it's time to make
a plan and decide what you need to do.
If it is something you're like,
oh man, I don't know any of
this, then, okay, time to study.
But you guys have been
doing well in these things.
So yep, you got it.
So with this one, how do you do it?
So you, same thing, another
valence electron one.
Um, the reason why it's very valence
electron heavy is because this is going
to be one of the concepts we're going
to use for covalent bonding, and we have
to be able to draw the structures, which
we're going to be doing on Chapter 6.
So right now we're on Chapter 5 for
everybody, so it's going to be soon.
Um, And, you know, the next couple of
weeks we'll do a lab with it where you're
going to be putting all these together
and showing how they share electrons,
which involves the Lewis dot structures.
So big thing is when you're doing
these, right, is you write the elemental
symbol and you put a dot on each side
of the atom, like it's in a box, right?
So you see with C, there was
four dots, one on each side.
And then when you, if you need
a fifth or sixth or seventh,
you then start doubling up.
So Each electron is like lonely.
It's kind of like, kind of like
Hund's rule, where everyone
is by themselves first.
How do you start doubling up?
Oh, so that's when, um, when you
get to that, that fifth electron,
that's when you start pairing them.
So kind of imagine that there's like,
well, because they're kind of our four
orbitals is what it's representing.
It's representing S and P.
So that's like why
there's only four sides.
There's three P orbitals
and one S orbital.
So the first thing is when
you're looking at it is look at
your conversions So you had 0.
125 grams of ampicillin and then you
said there's 250 milligrams in a 5
milliliter Uh, you know, shot essentially,
um, so you have two types of terms.
You have a term that's by
itself, and then a fraction.
You always start with the term that's
by itself, you never start with the
conversion term unless you have no choice.
So, when we do that The term that's
by itself is the grams, right?
You can't flip that value.
Um, we have grams that's on top.
You can't change it.
So it, it, it's something that you
can use as your starting point.
So after that, well, we want to be
able to bridge it to milliliters.
Well, how do we get there?
What's the common factor?
between these two things.
Well, I see I have grams and I have
grams or milligrams in the conversion.
So how do I go from grams to milligrams?
Well, that's when you gotta
look up your unit conversions.
So the first thing you gotta
ask yourself is, well, how
many milligrams are in a gram?
Well, when you, oops,
that's a highlighter.
When you do that, right, you'll quickly
see, right, 1 gram is 1, 000 milligrams.
We'll fill that in.
And then we can cancel our values.
If you're wondering where
I got a thousand, right?
It's the same thing as 10 to the minus
three grams is equal to one milligram.
So you could also use that
to, um, grams cancels.
And then we have our milligrams,
which we can then cancel with our last
conversion term, which is 250 milligrams.
Equivalent to five milliliters
and then we just cancel our units.
We're letting the units guide us.
We see that they're canceling.
It's getting to our goal.
And then we have milliliters
as our final unit.
I don't know why I keep
picking highlighter.
All right.
So then what we would do
is we multiply, right?
Point one, two, five
times 1000 times five.
And then we'll take that value and
then divide it by 250, and what we
should end up getting, I guess, would
be the answer, which was C, which is 2.
5 milliliters when you
do the math for that.
Okay?
And the reason it's two sig figs is
because the conversion term on the
right over here is two sig figs.
And these are three sig figs over here.
So that would be your final answer.
So this is a two step one.
This is like probably, you know,
this is the kind of dimensional
analysis that it could be.
You know, I tend to do drug related ones
because most you're in the health sciences
and it's a pretty common thing that you
have to calculate dosages and anything
that requires medicine, especially
when you get into the actual programs.
It's usually one of the Um, exam steps
that they have and it's one of those
things that you got to get like a, I think
they say you got to get 100 percent on it.
They don't let you move
on, um, to the next step.
So measuring out your how much
prescriptions and knowing all that
it's really important because you
don't want to accidentally overdose
a patient or underdose a patient too.
So how would you find the average
atomic mass for this Compound.
So it's like what you
did with the bead lab.
It's the exact same
thing, um, with isotopes.
This would probably be, like, arguably
one of the hardest math problems
you could have, just because, I
don't know, it's just a long one.
They're not crazy hard
to do, it's just long.
Yeah, it's a lot of plugging in
values and, okay, looks like the three
people that were able to get it did
get it, which is really good to see.
Um, there are a couple tricks
to this one, believe it or not.
So in a lot of times with the multiple
choice, you are able to eliminate answers.
Um, so when it comes to the
averages, what does that mean is
that your smallest value is 22.
17.
Your largest value is 24.
19.
So it has to be in between them, right?
What does that mean is, you can
eliminate B and C right off the bat.
There's no possible way for
that to be between your masses.
So it has to be A or D.
Now the thing is, you actually
probably can get, you might be able
to get the answer without even doing
the math here, if you use reasoning.
Because notice how the
first two are 90 percent.
That's the biggest weight of, of this.
So that tells you that the value
has to be probably between 922.
17 and 23.
18, which kind of really only
fits really D it's the only
one that's in between them.
So you can actually, there's a way to
reason through this without doing a single
thing of math, which is something you can
kind of always, if you understand percents
to like, where would it be weighted?
It's like a trick if you're running out of
time, let's say you have like five minutes
left, you haven't done six questions.
Pick the answer that's closest to the
highest weight of percentages, um, it
you have, you'd probably have a very
good chance of getting it correct.
If you had to take a blind guess, and some
of you maybe you did guess, I don't know.
But if you did, then you
did, you already did that.
But if you were to do the math, though,
so it's a pretty easy calculation to do.
The hardest part is remembering
that you can not use the
percents in their percent form.
You have to convert them to
decimals, and that's usually the
thing that most students forget.
So what you kind of do is, so this
was kind of like the lab with the
red, the black, and the white beads.
It's the same idea.
So what you do is you multiply
each of these sets of values.
So like for the first set, you multiply
them together for the second set.
You'll multiply them together,
and then for the third set, you'll
do the same thing, and you're
going to add those together.
So, kind of setting that
up, what do I mean by that?
So, we would take 22.
1760, we would multiply that times
the decimal of it, which is 0.
45, so that's this value here.
Let's convert it to decimal form.
Then like I mentioned, we're
going to add that to the next one.
So you take your mass again, 23.
1847.
Multiply that times.
The 0.
45 again because it's the other percent
and then you're going to add that
again to the next one, which was 24.
1934 times 10 percent this time and I'm
not too worried about the sig sig test.
You're just going to
write down your numbers.
You only include every single
zero in your work, right?
So once you do that, you'll
go through your math and what
you should get is about 22.
83 for your number and you got like 22.
831655 and then just round with the
four sig figs and we'll see that that
matches d in this case so that's how
you kind of do a problem like that it's
a little bit tougher but it's um that's
probably as hard as it could get because
i think i think that's the toughest
one or the order dimensional analysis
i think that one's tough too it just
kind of depends on which one you're not
as strong with all right based on the
compound mgcl2 What is the charge of MG?
So with this one, it's kind of the same
idea that you could do it two ways.
One is magnesium's charge is always
the same thing no matter what.
It's always two plus.
Um, so you could go through and
you could also do the reverse
swap drop if you want as well.
Um, you gotta be careful doing the reverse
swap drop because if it was reduced,
you could get the incorrect answer.
Um, I always kind of recommend going off
of your predictable charges for these.
So like with MgCl2, right?
Um, the charge for chlorine
is always negative one.
There's two of them.
So you know that The other charge
has to be 2 You could look it
up on the PRAC table as well.
So magnesium is always going
to do that, that exact trick.
Now, what I mentioned with the reversible
swap trap is you can take those values
and bring them back up here, but if it
was reduced, it will not be correct.
So it's kind of good to know at
least one of the ions to make
sure you're doing that correctly.
Unfortunately, I only do it.
usually on binary species and maybe
polyatomics, but I usually don't do
it for variable transition metals.
Uh, usually that's when
a mistake will happen.
Um, just because it could
be all kinds of numbers.
Okay.
So finally a density question.
So Catherine's been asking about that,
I think for like two hours, finally.
All right.
So, uh, so, um, all right.
Some gold has a mass of 521 grams.
It is added to 50 milliliters of water.
The water level rises to a
volume of 77 milliliters.
What is the density?
That's what it's asking.
So, this is what you did in lab, right?
So it's the displacement method.
So you got to kind of try to remember
that thought process because density
was, it is a really important conversion.
This is also like a, um, a very, very
common lab practical question, too.
It's pretty normal that, I've
seen it, A cop several semesters.
So when it comes to the lab practical, I
have a review video for that one too, but
there's, um, usually it's different every
semester, but this is a pretty common one.
The professors pick because
we come together and choose
how to make the practical to.
Standardized at 20 some sections of M3A.
And this is usually something like that.
We're not giving you 500 grams of gold,
but it's usually done with like aluminum
or something, but it's a pretty common.
thing that you might have
to do in five minutes.
Um, so when we're doing this, it
kind of is, it's a few things, right?
It's remembering what density is,
which is the first one, right?
So density is mass divided by volume.
Now the thing is one of the most
common mistakes that students do with
this one, which is maybe what you
guys did is they take the mass and
then they automatically divide it.
by the largest mass, or the largest, or
the final volume is what I should say.
And that's not the case, right?
So the way you want to do it is you want
to make sure you've got to calculate
what the volume of the object is,
not just use the volume of the water.
So what, what do you mean
by the volume of the object?
Well, that's the equivalent of Delta V,
or you can, if you want, you can define
it as volume of object if you want.
But Delta is usually what
we commonly use in a final.
minus initial.
So we, what we do is we take 77
milliliters, subtract it from 50
milliliters, and this would give us
our volume of our object because that's
what we dropped in to the liquid.
So we have 27 milliliters.
Now what we'll do is, with that, we'll
plug that into our formula, so we had
521 grams, and then we're gonna
divide that by our 27 milliliters,
and what we should get is 19.
3 grams per gram.
milliliter.
Okay.
Now, what other density questions
could you be asked to, you could
be given a density and you could be
asked like, well, what's the volume
of this or what's the mass of this?
So let's say if I, um, let's say
our gold was, um, oh, can't see.
Oh man.
Shoot.
Darn it.
Okay.
Let me bring it up.
Thanks.
Thanks for telling me.
All right.
So I ran over with this.
So the first thing I did, right,
just to kind of point it out real
quick is I wrote down Delta V.
I subtracted my volumes.
So it's 77 milliliters subtract from 50.
So it's final minus initial is
where those are coming from.
When that happens, right, that's
your volume of your object, so
that's where I got the 27 from.
Being that we only care about the
gold brock, we don't care about
the liquid, we just want to know
what our volume of our object is.
So once we have that, we'll plug
that into our density formula, right?
Density is equal to
mass divided by volume.
That's something you have to know.
Um, that you have to know density
is mass divided by volume.
So remember that because we do a
whole lab on it and it's something
that it's a conversion that's in like
all the homeworks, like all over the
place, mass divided by volume, right?
So 521 grams is what our mass was.
And then we're going to divide
that by the 27 milliliters.
When we do that, we get the
milliliter, which is the answer.
So the other way you could do this, a
problem could be done with density is
if it's used as a conversion factor.
So if I were to add, let's
say I found out that I have
found a 40 milliliter solution.
volume of gold and that's what
I had and I wanted to know how
much it weighed and let's say I
didn't have a balance available.
Well you could use density to
calculate what that mass is
so being that we have that 19.
3 as our density that's equivalent to one
milliliter so you could set this up as
a conversion factor which is something
to keep in mind it can be used as a
conversion term, um, which It's kind of
this most powerful part of its technique
is that allows you to bridge between
volume and mass, which is one of the
few things that allows us to do that.
Um, there might be a problem like
this though, like something like this
versus me, like making up some numbers.
Um, that might, that might be, I can't
remember if they're in here or not
camera, if I took it out or if I left
it, all right, we're almost done.
So let's try to finish it up.
So I'm also like, it's also
really late and I'm starting
to lose my voice From the day.
All right.
So if we were to name this, so
let's try and name this real quick
I know one of you still trying to
figure it out, but I'm gonna just
kind of lock it in for the time's
sake So, let's see how you guys did.
So you guys are split between
those are the two I was thinking
you'd be split between so When
do you use the Roman numeral?
So this is something I've
been talking about a lot today
with Monday Wednesday group.
You only use the Roman numeral
when it is not a predictable metal.
And when it is a transition metal,
so it has to be in the D block
and then it has to be predictable.
So the only ones you don't do it
for are aluminum, zinc, and silver.
Those ones you exclude the roman numeral
'cause you know they're charges, right?
Aluminum's three, uh,
zinc is two, silver's one.
So they're known.
It has to be one of the variable ones,
uh, that you, that you don't know it.
I'm happy that you get, you do
know the charge though, which is
aluminum three, but it would just be.
Aluminum in this case because it's
it's known it's it's a known value.
Okay.
What is the formula for copper one?
sulfide Yeah, you could say D block.
So it's a transition metals.
But yeah anything they're in the D block
That's when you use the Roman numerals.
So for this one, you do know two things,
you know, what the charge of copper
is It's being told to you and then
sulfur You can look it up for sulfur.
So, copper has a plus one charge.
Remember, the Roman numeral tells
you the charge, not the subscript.
Sulfur has a negative two charge.
So sulfide means sulfur.
So how many coppers would
you have to balance that?
Well you would need two
coppers to make that a reality.
So you should have Cu2S
should be the formula.
Oh boy, that should be
the formula for that one.
So why not CuS?
Well that's because sulfur's
charge is two minus.
So it needs to Remember, the Roman
numeral does not show the subscript,
um, when you're looking at these.
So, being that everybody got this
wrong, we should talk about it.
Um,
so let's, let me share this guy.
So, what this tells us.
This copper has a plus one charge.
Sulfur always has the exact
same charge no matter what.
So in this case, it has a
two minus charge, right?
When we look that up on our
Piroc table, it's on the second,
it's on the two minus column.
So what we'll do is we'd swap drop those
values, the two's going to come down and
then the one's going to come over here.
Then what we are going to have is
Cu2S as our answer.
So we got to make sure we swap drop it.
So, like, one of the big things I could
ask you, too, is if I ask you, like, what
is the charge of the cation in this case,
like, so, if I were to ask that, right,
the cation always refers to the metal.
So, in this case, it would be
one plus, if I ask you what the
charge of the anion, that would be.
Two minus, right?
So you could have, those are some
other questions you could have too.
I think there's some that's
like, some of the basics as well.
So, which one of these represents
the Lewis, the correct Lewis
dot structure for bromide ion?
I see that one of you has a question too.
I think that, oh, I can
get that about that big.
It's as big as I can go.
What's the charge for column
two to the left of sulfur?
So you mean two more, so like we're
caught for like where carbon is, you mean?
Or, or do you mean like
where beryllium is?
Car so carbon, carbon, we usually
don't say it has a charge.
On the white periodic table, this is
one thing I've been tempted to edit
from it, because on there it has,
I have plus four and minus four.
Those are representing, um, It's another
thing that we'll talk about later in
the semester called oxidation numbers.
It's a little, it's similar to
charges, but not quite the same thing.
Um, so the carbon column
usually does not get ionized.
So they usually do not have charges.
These are the species that do covalent
bonding, which is sharing electrons.
So you'll see them more in, um,
you know, next week or two when
we talk about covalent more.
Um, Yeah, the only ones you'll
see is, uh, when they're, when
they're involved with polyatomics.
Okay, that's when we were
split between two of them.
So, uh, Teal was correct.
Oh, no, three of them.
So why not, so what do we have?
We had one person picked D
and then two people picked C.
So C, so we got to read
this one carefully.
So it says the bromide ion, right?
So when it says that i ed ending, it's
referring to the ion, meaning that it
has one extra electron for bromine.
So that whole column has one extra.
So that means we're
gonna have one more dot.
The normal.
So when we're kind of drawing that, the
way to kind of go through it to show
your work and how to do this on your
homework, um, for this one too, when
you're drawing these and it's switching
over, the first thing I do is I will
write down my seven dots for bromine.
So the valence for bromine.
So I got 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9,
10, 11, 12, 13, But being that we're
referring to the ion that means that
it wants to achieve the octet rule So
it's gonna have one more now when it has
that extra one We put it in brackets to
represent that Hey This is an anion and
then we put the negative charge Outside
because it's saying that's being like
shared amongst the atom is how to show
that Um, so this is for the bromide
ion, and then this one would,
and then kind of just writing
the other one real quick.
This would be for the bromine than
if you were to have, let's say,
something that's positive and negative.
Well, let's say if you had N A,
so this would be sodium atom.
And then if you had sodium cation,
you just write a plus next to it.
So this would just be
sodium ion in this case.
So notice that the ending
didn't change for that one.
We just wrote sodium than ion.
Um, And that one, cause you got
to kind of label what they are.
And, and also in case I should, I
didn't mention this earlier, but I'll,
I'll post, I'll post all these notes
and stuff to canvas too for you guys.
So anything I broke down, I'm sure
there's probably one of you price, 308
photos on your phone at this point, but
all this stuff's going to be on canvas.
So you'll have it all.
So you don't have to do any of that
or screenshots or go through whatever,
you know, you'll have everything.
Let's see how much I
got to zoom on this one.
What is the charge of
the nitrate polyatomic?
So that one should be a pretty easy one
because you guys have your green sheet.
So you don't want to get confused
between nitrate and nitrogen, right?
So nitrogen, you're right,
it would be a three minus.
But when it comes to nitrate or
nitrite, so for your polyatomics,
so your oxyanions, they have a
negative one charge for those ones.
What is the formula for the molecule
formed between nitrogen and chlorine?
Um, it actually has to
do with Lewis structures.
So this is a preview of what's to come.
Uh, so there won't be a nitrogen
chlorine one on that test.
Sorry.
It's almost 10 o'clock.
It's like, ah.
All right.
So with this one, right?
We write our dots, right?
There's five dots around
nitrogen for the five valence.
And then there's seven
around the chlorine.
So this is where they share, right?
If I were to look at this, well,
chlorine only needs one electron.
So what can it do?
Well, it can bond.
with nitrogen, where it can share
one of its electrons to make a bond.
And then once we do that, well, I could
add more chlorines to do the same thing.
Um, so if I do this same idea, right, I
have the seven dots for chlorine, I can
also share that one electron where they
come together, and then I can add in
the other one too, and then as a result,
they're all gonna have a complete octet.
So this is covalent bonding.
It doesn't give, it doesn't take,
it doesn't give, they share.
So with the two dots, the,
whenever the yellow and the purple
dots are, this is showing that
two electrons are being shared.
And as a result, when you're looking at
these, well, if you, if I highlight maybe
in green, around chlorine, these are
the eight electrons that chlorine has.
For nitrogen, these are the eight
electrons that technically nitrogen has.
And then you can see the
other chlorine also has eight.
And this one also
considered to have eight.
So they're all happy.
Every single one of them.
They all have their complete octet.
So there's nothing about giving,
taking, it doesn't have to
get it from anywhere else.
So it ends up being a
covalent bonded example.
So this is what we'll talk
about, um, more in week seven?
I think week seven.
Week seven or eight.
You see it goes off the Lewis structures.
So yeah, I forgot that's in there.
So that's it.
I took that out of this test for you guys
cause I didn't want to, um, as you all
know, it's already overwhelming as it is.
So this was like one extra
thing that was in there.
So I took out covalent bonding, like
almost all together, like the naming
video is there for everybody for both
classes, but I took it out, like we're
not going to really cover it in day
to detail until like a few more weeks.
So I separated ionic and covalent.
Last one.
Oh, where was there?
Yay.
All right.
Last question.
Which of the following electron
configurations is impossible?
Oh boy.
That's tiny.
Whoa.
Oh crap.
I just skipped all of you guys.
I'm so sorry.
Oh, which one's impossible?
Oh no.
I just did not mean to skip that.
I'll try to zoom in.
I'm sorry.
All right.
Let's just look at it together
then and see if we can figure
out which one is impossible.
So this is the one that I
was kind of referring to.
Earlier, when we're like looking at
this, like, can you try to figure out
what's considered to be impossible?
So you're like looking at each
configuration, seeing if you see
anything out of the ordinary.
So like, 1s2 is good.
2s2, you see an A, that there's, it's 2s4.
So that's letting you know
like, ooh, that's wrong.
So A is something very, very wrong with A.
Then you kind of compare the other
ones, like 2P6, 3S2, and then all the
3Ps, well that's going between 1 and 6.
Now, the question was,
well, what is impossible?
So that one would be A, because one of
them, you can't have 2S4, it stops at 2.
So remember it's 2S2, 2P6.
Other ways this could be impossible is
like, um, maybe if, uh, they're in the
wrong order maybe, or like, incomplete
levels is another thing as well.
So those are the kind of
questions that that's asking.
Sorry, that was an accident.
See, like I said, I'm
getting tired of brain.
But, alright, it's not 2023 anymore.
But, it's my 2023 exam,
is what that means.
I should have not put the year in there.
Good job, guys.
Nice.
That's B.
Aubrey.
Is that Aubrey?
No, that's Audrey, not Aubrey.
What was B?
Oh, is that um, No.
Oh, there's a list that's on there.
I didn't look at everybody who's left yet.
I was like, who can I guess?
Oh, is it Brenda?
Are you doing it?
Yeah, he's like, It's like, that would
probably be Brenda, I would guess,
would be the most likely case for B.
Good job.
I don't know who else it would be.
You're the only one with a B in your name.
Good job, Catherine, Audrey.
Nice.
Awesome.
Well, good job, guys.
Well, that's, that was
one of my old exams.
So I know it was a lot longer
than I thought this would be.
I thought it would just take
like an hour, maybe two hours
to kind of go through that.
But I hope that it helped.
Um, and Uh, kind of going through an
old test and kind of reviewing all
those things and going through them.
Um, is there any like, last minute
questions that anybody has at all?
Like, I don't know, anything that, I
don't, I think that was kind of covered.
All the major areas of the test that
I can think of, I'm going to look at
the test real quick just to make sure
that, you know, this is not something
I haven't said that I'm going to be
like, I'm going to regret that later.
Delivery period naming, group naming?
Um, there could be.
I mean, that's possible for sure.
I mean, you should know at least like
the You should know those four groups.
I think like the alkali,
alkaline, halogens, noble gases.
I think that's, I think that's
pretty valuable to know those names.
They're so common in terms of like the
everyday world and like in terms of
being used, not only chemistry, but bio,
that the terminology comes up a lot.
So I think it, it is helpful.
to to know them, um,
especially for later classes.
Yeah.
I don't think it's so much.
I, you know, I'm like, I was
like, I gotta eat dinner.
I haven't eaten dinner yet.
So I'm like, that's why I'm like,
I'm just kind of starting to lose it.
Um, so I know, right?
That's I never remember to eat, never
ever feed myself, but I hope it's helped.
Um, you know, send me messages.
You guys need help while
you're studying and stuff.
Absolutely.
And for your homework
and all that good stuff.
Okay.
And then, um, Yeah, if being that so many
people help with this one and if maybe
I'll send you guys like a ask you guys
how it helped and stuff and hopefully
you guys grade so study make sure you
guys study like a lot of hours hours
and hours and that doesn't mean like
watching Netflix while studying like
or blasting music while studying like
try to focus lo fi is okay but you know
don't go Ham, you know, all right guys.
I hope you all have a good night
I'll see y'all later and let me know
if you guys need anything at all.
All right.
Bye now.
See ya